<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LSF on Alessandra [Ali] Valcarcel</title>
    <link>/tags/lsf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LSF on Alessandra [Ali] Valcarcel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 21:01:01 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/lsf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Quality Control</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-09-31-qualitycontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-09-31-qualitycontrol/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the ninth blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on various ways to quality control jobs running on the cluster. Most commands covered work for both normal and interactive sessions.
The first time the command appears below it is hyperlinked to the manual or reference material. All the commands listed and linked to references in the last section of the post All Commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Batch Jobs and Normal Sessions</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-13-normalsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-13-normalsession/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the eighth blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on normal sessions and submitting batch jobs.
Initializing a normal session and submitting a batch job is an advanced topic but you’ll still be requesting appropriate system parameters using the LSF bsub command. We will again focus on the bsub for a normal session and common advanced options associated with the bsub to request more cores for parallelization, force memory constraints on your session, and request certain machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Advanced Topics for Interactive Sessions</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-01-interactivesession2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-01-interactivesession2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the seventh blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on advanced topics related to interactive sessions.
Though this post centers around advanced content related to interactive sessions, you’ll still be requesting appropriate system parameters using the LSF bsub command. We focus here on more advanced options associated with the bsub to request more cores for parallelization, force memory constraints on your session, and request certain machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Interactive Session Basics</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-06-12-interactivesession1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-06-12-interactivesession1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the sixth blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on the basics of using an interactive session.
Interactive sessions are opened by requesting appropriate system parameters using the LSF bsub command. Once a session is open you can run your code on the loaded host interactively. This allows you to work dynamically on your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Session Types</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-06-05-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-06-05-sessions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the fifth blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on the types of sessions available on the Penn HPC and when to use the different types.
There are two types of sessions you can request when working on the cluster. An interactive session or a normal session. I will discuss each in more detail below and in future posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Terminology and Specifications</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-27-terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-27-terminology/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the fourth blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on the general terminology surrounding high performance computing clusters and an overview of the CCEB cluster specifications.
Most of the information presented in this article was taken from IBM resources here and Microsoft here. You should explore these sites on your own for specific details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Logging Onto The Cluster</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-23-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 21:01:01 -2000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-23-ssh/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the third blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on logging onto the cluster and transfer remote clients.
 Logging On In order to log onto the cluster you must have an account. For more resources on getting started and the cluster details are provided here. As of April 15, 2019 Martin Das (lablu@pennmedicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Command Line</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-14-commandline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 21:05:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-14-commandline/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the second blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on basics of command line.
 Folder Versus Directory Most people use the terms folder and directory interchangeably. From a programmers point of view though there is a slight distinction. A directory is file organization system while a folder is the graphical user interface that is used to represent a directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Introduction</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-13-clusterintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-13-clusterintro/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I’ve decided to dedicate the next few blog posts to using the Penn Medicine Academic Computing Services High-Performance Computing Cluster. I’ll loosely refer to the Penn HPC simply as the cluster, the CCEB cluster, the PMACs HPC, and the Penn HPC throughout this series of blog posts. These posts are intended for both beginners and advanced users and will include information about:
Basics in command line Definitions and vocabulary Logging onto the cluster PMACS high performance computing (HPC) grid specifications Session types Parallelizing code Quality controlling your jobs Bash aliases  This series is designed by a student for students specifically in biostatistics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>