<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alessandra [Ali] Valcarcel</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alessandra [Ali] Valcarcel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Game of Thrones Data</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-04-1-r-rmarkdown-got-scrape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-04-1-r-rmarkdown-got-scrape/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I am going to cover the basics to creating a website using blogdown and Hugo. We will create and deploy a template website as well as cover some basics about changing content. You should be extremely comfortable coding in R, writing in R Markdown, and have a working knowledge of GitHub. You should have R, R Studio, R Markdown all installed on your computer and an account on GitHub before we start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Personal Website with blogdown</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-03-15-r-rmarkdown-blogdown-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-03-15-r-rmarkdown-blogdown-basics/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I am going to cover the basics to creating a website using blogdown and Hugo. We will create and deploy a template website as well as cover some basics about changing content. You should be extremely comfortable coding in R, writing in R Markdown, and have a working knowledge of GitHub. You should have R, R Studio, R Markdown all installed on your computer and an account on GitHub before we start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>Alessandra [Ali] Valcarcel Born in Miami, FL Lives in Philadelphia, PA Education:
Ph.D. Biostatistics (anticipated 2020)
University of Pennsylvania
M.S. Biostatistics (2017)
University of Pennsylvania
B.A. Biology and Statistics (Honors) (2015)
University of Connecticut
Select Publications:
2018 - Journal of Neuroimaging. &amp;ldquo;MIMoSA: An Automated Method for Intermodal Segmentation Analysis of Multiple Sclerosis Brain Lesions.&amp;rdquo;
2017 - Frontiers in Genetics. &amp;ldquo;Illustrating, Quantifying and Correcting for Bias in Post-hoc Analysis of Gene-Based Rare Variant Tests of Association.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently a third-year PhD student in Biostatistics in the Department of Biostatistics, Epidemiology, and Informatics at the University of Pennsylvania. I am an active researcher in the PennSIVE working group under the mentorship of Russell [Taki] Shinohara. Primarily, my research interests lie in the development of statistical methods for analyzing neuroimaging data sets with the goal of understanding disease processes in the brain. Currently, my projects involve the analysis of multi-sequence structural MRI for the study of multiple sclerosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>I am motivated by current scientific questions to develop general, principled methods for the analysis of data arising from neuroimaging studies. My work balances ideas from machine learning algorithms and feature extraction development in order to develop data analysis tools required to solve problems in structural imaging data sets in a clinically meaningful manner. Specifically, I am interested in developing statistical methods to advance automated lesion detection in multiple sclerosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/</guid>
      <description>MIMoSA 
The mimosa R package is now live on Neuroconductor. This package allows you to implement the MIMoSA method discussed in our paper to automatically segment white matter lesions. The package comes with some pre-trained models if you do not have manual segmentations to train the model. If you do have manual segmentations, we suggest you train the model with your data. You can access the page directly here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>