<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alessandra [Ali] Valcarcel</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alessandra [Ali] Valcarcel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 21:05:01 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining your Own Apple Music Data</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-10-02-apple_music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 21:05:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-10-02-apple_music/</guid>
      <description>Streaming services like Pandora, Apple Music, and Spotify have changed how we consume music. In the olden days of purchasing music, whether a physical CD or through iTunes, users had to seek out music and make decisive choices about the music they were choosing to buy. Additionally, you had a physical or digital copy of the music you were consuming. If you wanted to listen to music you would have to look through your CD collection or scroll through your iTunes library and select what you wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for the Job Market</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-10-01-job_advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-10-01-job_advice/</guid>
      <description>It is never too early to start preparing for the job market. You never know who you’ll meet and what advice or opportunities they might be able to offer you. If you’re prepared it makes exploiting connections and navigating the job market much easier.
When I first started graduate school I really had no idea what I wanted to do beyond graduate school. Academia, industry, or government all seemed appealing for different reasons and I wasn’t quite sure yet which field would align with my wants and needs best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grad School: What I&#39;ve Learned (so far at least)</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-09-04-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-09-04-advice/</guid>
      <description>While the end of summer doesn’t always guarantee cooler weather it does always mean the start of a fresh and new school year.
   via GIPHY  I’ve been enrolled in full time school of some sort for 23 straight years now including pre-k and grad school. As a fifth year PhD student, I’m starting to get nostalgic that this is likely (and hopefully) my last year in school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Commands and References</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-09-03-references/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-09-03-references/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the tenth and final blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post includes all the commands and references used throughout the series.
 Commands The commands presented below are sometimes generalizations of what was presented throughout the series.
Command Line # Change the working directory cd # List folders/files in a directory ls # Report working directory pwd # Move files or directories mv # Copy files or directories cp # Summons the manual man # Create a directory mkdir # Removes a directory rmdir # Removes files or a directory rm # Clear the screen/command board in Terminal clear # Uses all files with the pattern indicated in the command applied *pattern* # Creates an empty text file touch   Log On ssh -X pennkey@scisub  Screen # Screen the session while on the scisub host screen # Check how many screens you have open screen -ls # Resuming a screen screen -r  Interactive Session # Full bsub for an interactive session bsub -Is -q cceb_interactive -m &amp;quot;silver01&amp;quot; -n 8 -R &amp;quot;span[hosts=1] rusage[mem=5000]&amp;quot; -M 10000 &amp;quot;bash&amp;quot; # R code to detect the number of cores requested by bsub # Recall parallel::detectCores() does not report the proper number Sys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Quality Control</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-08-31-qualitycontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-08-31-qualitycontrol/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the ninth blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on various ways to quality control jobs running on the cluster. Most commands covered work for both normal and interactive sessions.
The first time the command appears below it is hyperlinked to the manual or reference material. All the commands listed and linked to references in the last section of the post All Commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Batch Jobs and Normal Sessions</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-13-normalsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-13-normalsession/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the eighth blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on normal sessions and submitting batch jobs.
Initializing a normal session and submitting a batch job is an advanced topic but you’ll still be requesting appropriate system parameters using the LSF bsub command. We will again focus on the bsub for a normal session and common advanced options associated with the bsub to request more cores for parallelization, force memory constraints on your session, and request certain machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Advanced Topics for Interactive Sessions</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-01-interactivesession2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-01-interactivesession2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the seventh blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on advanced topics related to interactive sessions.
Though this post centers around advanced content related to interactive sessions, you’ll still be requesting appropriate system parameters using the LSF bsub command. We focus here on more advanced options associated with the bsub to request more cores for parallelization, force memory constraints on your session, and request certain machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Interactive Session Basics</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-06-12-interactivesession1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-06-12-interactivesession1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the sixth blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on the basics of using an interactive session.
Interactive sessions are opened by requesting appropriate system parameters using the LSF bsub command. Once a session is open you can run your code on the loaded host interactively. This allows you to work dynamically on your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Session Types</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-06-05-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-06-05-sessions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the fifth blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on the types of sessions available on the Penn HPC and when to use the different types.
There are two types of sessions you can request when working on the cluster. An interactive session or a normal session. I will discuss each in more detail below and in future posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Terminology and Specifications</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-27-terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 21:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-27-terminology/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the fourth blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on the general terminology surrounding high performance computing clusters and an overview of the CCEB cluster specifications.
Most of the information presented in this article was taken from IBM resources here and Microsoft here. You should explore these sites on your own for specific details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Logging Onto The Cluster</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-23-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 21:01:01 -2000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-23-ssh/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the third blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on logging onto the cluster and transfer remote clients.
 Logging On In order to log onto the cluster you must have an account. For more resources on getting started and the cluster details are provided here. As of April 15, 2019 Martin Das (lablu@pennmedicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Command Line</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-14-commandline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 21:05:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-14-commandline/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the second blog post in a series of articles about using the CCEB cluster. An overview of the series is available here. This post focuses on basics of command line.
 Folder Versus Directory Most people use the terms folder and directory interchangeably. From a programmers point of view though there is a slight distinction. A directory is file organization system while a folder is the graphical user interface that is used to represent a directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the CCEB High Performance Computing Cluster: Introduction</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-13-clusterintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-13-clusterintro/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I’ve decided to dedicate the next few blog posts to using the Penn Medicine Academic Computing Services High-Performance Computing Cluster. I’ll loosely refer to the Penn HPC simply as the cluster, the CCEB cluster, the PMACs HPC, and the Penn HPC throughout this series of blog posts. These posts are intended for both beginners and advanced users and will include information about:
Basics in command line Definitions and vocabulary Logging onto the cluster PMACS high performance computing (HPC) grid specifications Session types Parallelizing code in interactive and normal sessions Quality controlling your jobs Bash aliases  This series is designed by a student for students specifically in biostatistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Maester-Level Network Analysis of Game of Thrones</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-05-gotapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-05-gotapp/</guid>
      <description>Warning: This post contains spoilers for Game of Thrones seasons 1-7.
Like 16.5+ million people across the globe, I anxiously await the return of the eighth and final season of Game of Thrones (GoT) on April, 14, 2019. After a two year hiatus, I wanted to refresh my memory on the plot lines across seasons 1 through 7 before HBO wraps up the conflict.
In preparation, I decided to evaluate the statistical networks between characters across seasons 1 through 7 to consider how the network of characters has changed over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMI R-Hack-A-Pack: Package creation - From functions to a (GitHub) package</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-06-04-rpackage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-06-04-rpackage/</guid>
      <description> Download my slides for SMI 2018 R-Hack-A-Pack. I covered Package creation: From function to a GitHub Package.
 Download Slides  For the .Rmd you can download here.
 Download .Rmd  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Game of Thrones Data</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-04-1-r-rmarkdown-got-scrape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-04-1-r-rmarkdown-got-scrape/</guid>
      <description>WARNING: This post contains spoilers for Game of Thrones and some foul language reproduced from the show script
April may as well be Game of Thrones (GoT) month. For 7 loyal years, fans eagerly await April as the premiere of the new season. The final season is no different and will yet again return in April…2019 bypassing a season in 2018.
  As a loyal fan I’m determined to not let my April 2018 be any different and am dedicating a few blog posts to GoT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Personal Website with blogdown</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-03-15-r-rmarkdown-blogdown-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-03-15-r-rmarkdown-blogdown-basics/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I am going to cover the basics to creating a website using blogdown and Hugo. We will create and deploy a template website as well as cover some basics about changing content. You should be extremely comfortable coding in R, writing in R Markdown, and have a working knowledge of GitHub. You should have R, R Studio, R Markdown all installed on your computer and an account on GitHub before we start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>Alessandra [Ali] Valcarcel Born in Miami, FL Lives in Philadelphia, PA Education:
Ph.D., Biostatistics
University of Pennsylvania
Advisors: Drs. Kristin Linn and Russell [Taki] Shinohara
Thesis Title: Statistical Methods for Multi-Modal Image Analysis with Applications in Multiple Sclerosis and Neurodevelopment
(anticipated May 2020)
M.S., Biostatistics
University of Pennsylvania
Advisor: Dr. Russell [Taki] Shinohara
Thesis Title: MIMoSA: An Automated Method for Intermodal Segmentation Analysis of Multiple Sclerosis Brain Lesions
(2017)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently a fifth-year doctoral student studying Biostatistics in the Department of Biostatistics, Epidemiology, and Informatics at the University of Pennsylvania. I am an active researcher within the PennSIVE Center under the co-mentorship of Russell [Taki] Shinohara and Kristin Linn.
Primarily, my research interests lie in the development of statistical methods for analyzing neuroimaging data sets with the goal of understanding disease processes in the brain. Currently, my projects involve the analysis of multi-sequence structural MRI to study neurodevelopment and multiple sclerosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>I am motivated by current scientific questions to develop general, principled methods for the analysis of data arising from neuroimaging studies. My work balances ideas from classification using machine learning and novel feature exploration in order to develop data analysis tools required to solve problems in structural imaging data sets in a clinically meaningful manner. Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in developing statistical methods for multi-modal analysis to better characterize and understand neurodevelopment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/</guid>
      <description>MIMoSA 
The R package mimosa is now live on Neuroconductor with the development version on GitHub. This package allows you to implement the MIMoSA method discussed in our original paper and follow up paper to automatically segment both T2 hyperintense lesions and T1 hypointense lesions. The package comes with some pre-trained models if you do not have manual segmentations to train the model. If you do have manual segmentations, we suggest you train the model with your data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>